Guide to the Joanna and Susan Horner Letters, 1847-1894 MS 134
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Joanna and Susan Horner Letters
1847-1894
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Horner, Susan
MS 134
0.1 Linear Feet 1 folder
Correspondents writing to the Ms. Horners include Ellen Kean, F. Maurice, Harriet Hosmer, C.P. Marsh, E. Ryan, H.H. Hilman, Sir James Hudson, Rose Kingsley, Sir H.E. Bunbury, Francis Cobbe, and Sir James Clark. The letters deal with Walks in Florence, Italian affairs, and refer to Eastlake, the Lyells, Royalties, Froude and more. Included is one letter to Leonard Horner from Lord Landsdowne.
Biographical Note
Joanna Horner (born 1823) and Susan Horner (1816-1900) were daughters of Leonard Horner (1785-1864), a geologist and social reformer, co-founder of the Edinburg Review and politician. Both were writers on Italian subjects and co-authored Walks in Florence and its Environs (London,1873). Among Susan Horner's works is A Century of Despotism in Naples and Sicily (Edinburg, 1860). Their eldest sister, Mary, (born 1809) was married to the geologist Charles Lyell. Both Joanna and Susan remained unmarried.
Scope and Contents
Correspondents writing to the Ms. Horners include Ellen Kean, F. Maurice, Harriet Hosmer, C.P. Marsh, E. Ryan, H.H. Hilman, Sir James Hudson, Rose Kingsley, Sir H.E. Bunbury, Frances Cobbe, and Sir James Clark. The letters deal with Walks in Florence, Italian affairs, and refer to Eastlake, the Lyells, Royalties, Froude, etc. Included is one letter to Leonard Horner from Lord Landsdowne.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Provenance
Purchased from Myers (dealer), May 1958..
Arrangement
These letters have been arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the correspondent.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Horner, Joanna; Horner, Susan
- Series I: Correspondence 1874-1894
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, March 18, 1847 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Joanna Horner, May 8, 1849 (Folder 1)
  - H.H. Hilman to Susan Horner, February 19, 1850 (Folder 1)
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, July 11, 1856 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Ms. Horner, June 25, 1857 (Folder 1)
  - Obituary and Funeral Notice Re: Sir Henry Edward Bunbury. Bury Post, April 17 and 24, 1860 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown (Bishop of London?) to Ms. Horner, March 5, 1864 (Folder 1)
  - George Marsh? To Ms. Horner, June 7, 1867 (Folder 1)
  - E. Ryan to Ms. Horner, September 28, 1872 (Folder 1)
  - E. Ryan to Ms. Horner, May 9, 1873 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown (E. Ryan?) to Ms. Horner, June 30, 1873 (letter incomplete) (Folder 1)
  - E. Ryan to Ms. Horner, April 21, 1874 (Folder 1)
  - James Hudson to Madam (Ms. Horner), May 11 1874 (Folder 1)
  - E. Ryan to Ms. Horner, March 4, 1875 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to unknown, March 7, 1875 (letter incomplete) (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Ms. Horner, March 13, 1875 (Folder 1)
  - Unknown (cannot read) to Ms. Horner, June 25, 1875(?) (Folder 1)
  - Sir George Treurlyan(?) to Ms. Horner, January 11, 1878 (Folder 1)
  - James Hudson to Ms. Horner, April 30,1878 (Folder 1)
  - H.H. Hilman to Susan Horner, May (?), 1881 (Folder 1)
  - Blanch Willis Howard to unknown, November 16, 1881 (letter incomplete) (Folder 1)
  - Sir James Clark to Susan Horner, November 23, 1882 (Folder 1)
  - Susan Horner to unknown, May 15, 1885 (Folder 1)
  - Rose Kingsley to Miss Horner, September 4, 1894 (Folder 1)
- Series II: Correspondence, undated
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, January 21, (year not given, but 1860 or earlier) (Folder 1)
  - James Hudson to Ms. Horner, March 3, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - Ellen Kean to Ms. Horner, March 23, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, March 30, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - F. Maurice to Ms. Horner, May 28, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - Unknown to Ms. Horner, June 2, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, July 16, (year not given, likely 1861) (Folder 1)
  - Lord Landsdowne to Leonard Hunter, July 27, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - H.E. Bunbury to Susan Horner, September 7, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - Francis Cobbe to Ms. Horner, October 4, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - Harriet Hosmer to Ms. Horner, March 8, (year not given) (Folder 1)
  - Harriet Hosmer to Ms. Horner, no date (Folder 1)
  - Harriet Hosmer to Ms. Horner, no date (Folder 1)